我喜欢你的衬衫
I like your suit.
谢谢 为了工作 我买了几套新衣服
Oh, thanks. Got a couple new outfits for work.
知道你未婚妻的工作就是
How does it feel knowing your fiancee's job
打扮时髦地出去和医生调情
is to go out and flirt with doctors,
而你穿着旧衣服坐在这里...
looking like that, while you sit here, you know...
是什么感觉?
looking like this?
她不会和医生调情的
She doesn't flirt with doctors.
对 我很专业的
Yeah. It's all very professional.
你知道你弯腰的时候 我能看到你的胸吧?
You know when you bend over, I can see down your shirt?
知道 很好
Okay, good.
说到新工作 暗物质
Speaking of new careers, how are things going
研究得怎么样啊 Sheldon?
with dark matter, Sheldon?
我得说这是暗物质研究领域历史上
Oh, yeah, I'd have to say it's the most exiting time
- 最激动人心的时刻  - 哦
- in the history of the field.  - Oh.
有什么进展?
What's going on?
因为我开始研究了
I started doing it.
知道吗 政府资助了
You know, the government funded
有史以来最大的试验 用来探测暗物质
the biggest experiment yet to detect dark matter.
对呀
Oh, yeah,
我还看到了... 他们要派研究小组
I've read about that... they're sending research teams
- 去那些废弃的盐矿  - 要知道 Sheldon
- down into abandoned salt mines.  - You know, Sheldon,
如果我们申请加入那种小组
if we apply to be one of those teams,
我们就成为了某个伟大成就的奠基人...
we could be on the ground floor of something big...
而不只是理论物理和理论天体物理学家了
not just for theoretical physics but for astrophysics as well.
等等... 你们要去矿洞里工作?
Wait, hang on... you guys are gonna work in a mine?
- 不行吗?  - 我们上次
- Why not?  - You had
去洗个车 你就恐慌症发作了
a panic attack when we went through the car wash.
也许你说的情绪 应该是我对你竟然去洗东西
Perhaps the emotion you're referring to was shock
表露出的惊讶之情
at you having something cleaned.
我觉得Penny的意思是 你们两个进矿洞工作
I think what Penny meant is, the thought of you two
这事有点搞笑... 就像是猫骑在扫地机器人上
in a mine is kind of funny... it's like a cat riding a Roomba.
如果他们害怕 就可以戴那种
If they get scared, they'll have those hats
有灯的帽子 因为那下面
with the lights on them, 'cause down there
一年到头都是黑漆漆的!
it's night-night all the time!
也许他们可以
Maybe they could
驾驶那种矿车穿梭矿洞
ride around in one of those mine carts that go,
咯吱咯吱咯吱
ee-oo-ee-oo-ee-oo.
没错 等他们看到鬼 就能快速逃掉了!
Yeah, it'll help them get away when they see a gh-gh-ghost...!
- 他们是在取笑我们吗?  - 没错
- Are they making fun of us?  - Yup.
真怀念我年少无知的时候
I miss the old days when I couldn't tell.
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第八季第6集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子   时间轴: pisces夜
翻译: 影子酱 轮子君 UU爆炸了   校对: UU爆炸了
我一直以来最喜欢的游戏之一
So, one of my favorite video games of all time
是"旺达与巨像" 但只能在
is called Shadow of the Colossus, and it was only
PS2平台玩
for PlayStation 2,
但之后他们终于开发了PS3平台版本
but then they came out with a new version
画质更好
for PS3 with better graphics.
我终于有机会能玩了
I finally got the chance to play it,
但不知道为什么 就是没有第一个那么好玩了
and for some reason, it just wasn't as good as the first one.
要不我们说聊瑜伽的事吧
Or something about yoga.
抱歉... 我在想工作的事情
I'm sorry... I was thinking about work.
我刚才在说一个游戏...
Well, I was just saying that there was this video game...
没错 我就是那时候开始想工作的事情的
Yeah, that's when I started thinking about work.
听着 我有点好消息要宣布
Uh, listen, I've got some good news.
恩
Hmm.
这是给你的
This is for you.
唔
Huh.
这是什么?
What is this?
你知道他们给我发了公车吧?
Well, you know how they gave me the company car?
我也不需要两辆车 所以就把另一辆卖掉了
Didn't make sense to have two, so I sold the other one.
我给你的那辆?
The one I gave you?
对呀 就把钱还给你了... 现在我们扯平了
Yeah. And there's your money back... and now we're even.
多好呀
How great is that?
是呀
Uh, yeah.
怎么了?
What?
没什么
Nothing.
拜托 Leonard 我知道那辆车是你体贴的表现
Oh, come on, Leonard, I know the car was a thoughtful gesture
我真的很感激
and I really appreciate it,
但我真的不需要两辆车
but it doesn't make sense to have both.
- 说得对  - 那我该怎么办?
- You're right.  - What should I have done?
拍张我们坐在车里的照片 放在粉色相框里
Taken a picture of us in the car and put it in a pink frame
框上还写着"绝世好未婚夫"吗?
with puffy paint around it that says "best fiance ever"?
听起来也不赖
Doesn't sound that bad.
好 因为... 我就这么干了!
Well, good, because... that's why I did!
哦...
Oh...
谢谢
thank you.
- 真是... 太贴心了  - 其实也没
- That... that is so sweet.  - No, it's not
那么贴心... 我是用你的钱
that sweet... I paid for the frame
买了相框 然后还去做了个按摩
with your money and then got a massage.
好吧 你不必把这些钱给我的
You know what, you don't have to give me this.
你留着
You keep it.
- 为什么?  - 那辆车
- Why?  - The car
是个礼物... 是你当时需要的东西
was a gift... it was something you needed.
我很高兴能帮到你
I was happy to help you out.
我真的很感激 但现在我不需要了
And I really appreciate it, but now I don't need it,
- 所以... 还给你  - 好吧
- so... here you go.  - Well,
这太傻了... 你不需要那辆车
this is silly... so you don't need the car,
但你可以用这些钱给自己买点东西
but you could use it to buy yourself something else,
比如... 买个能把这些钱放进去的皮夹
like a... new purse to put all this money in.
亲爱的 我可以自己买
Sweetie, I can buy my own stuff.
我现在有个不错的工作
I have a good job now.
我知道 我也很为你自豪
I know, and I'm proud of you,
但并不意味着我就不能做点贴心的事情呀
but that doesn't mean I can't do something nice.
比如这个
Like this.
好吧 我不想和你吵架
Okay, I don't want this to turn into a fight.
- 我也不想  - 很好
- I don't, either.  - Great.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 能把盐罐递给我吗?  - 好的
- Can you pass the salt, please?  - Sure.
我还以为按喜剧剧情来 可以缓解紧张的局面
In my mind, that broke the tension with comedy
还能促成嘿咻
and led to sex.
嘿 Sheldon 你忙吗?
Hey, Sheldon, you busy?
我一直很忙
I'm always busy.
我的大脑能够高速多任务工作
This mind is capable of advanced multitasking.
要知道 就现在
You know, currently,
我正在努力解开
I'm attempting to solve
彭罗斯猜想
the Penrose conjecture,
也在写等我解开彭罗斯猜想
I'm composing my Nobel acceptance speech
拿到诺贝尔奖时的获奖演说
for when I've solved the Penrose conjecture,
还在想美人鱼是怎么生孩子的
and I'm wondering how mermaids have babies.
它们不是在石头上生蛋吗?
Don't they lay eggs on a rock?
现在我空出脑子做另一件事了
Now I've got room for another thing.
你有什么事?
What do you want?
所以我做了点小调查
So, I did a little research on what
在矿洞里的工作环境什么的
the conditions are like in the mines,
也许大家说得对...
and the guys might be right...
下面的生活很艰苦
sounds pretty rough down there.
首先 那下面很潮湿
For starters, it's very humid,
气温大概有一百华氏度
and about a hundred degrees.
我是德州来的 你是印度来的...
Well, I'm from Texas and you're from India...
腋下的味道我们闻得也不少 下一条
we're no strangers to the fragrant armpit. Next.
那个矿洞还没被废弃 所以离我们不远的地方
It's also a live mine, so there'll be dynamite explosions
- 可能会有爆破  - 好吧 我有个
- going off in the distance.  - Yeah, I have
患有乳糖不耐症
a lactose-intolerant roommate
还吃冰激凌的室友 下一条
with a taste for ice cream. Next.
一次得在矿下待12个小时
Oh, you have to be down there for 12 hours at a time.
是吗? 我们总得待在那儿的
Yeah? We have to be somewhere.
好吧 那边没有厕所...
Well, there's no toilets...
所以我们得在一个桶里解决
we'll have to do our business in a bucket.
就这么定了... 我们不去了
So it's settled... we're not doing it.
听着 我明白 但是... 在我们放弃
Look, I get it, but... before we pass up
一次绝好机会之前 我一直在想
on an incredible opportunity, I was thinking about
Howard做宇航员训练的时候
when Howard was training to go to space,
他们会让他待在个模拟环境里面
they put him in a simulated environment.
真有趣 你是想说我们得
Interesting. You're suggesting that we recreate
模拟矿下的环境
the conditions of the mine
- 看看是否能忍受  - 没错
- to see if we can handle it.  - Exactly.
- 很好  - 那我们该去哪里模拟?
- Very well.  - So where should we do it?
我来谷歌"又热 又黑 又湿"
Well, I'll just Google "hot, dark and moist,"
看看能查到什么
see what comes up.
呃 Sheldon...
Uh, Sheldon...
噢 这里 看呀 查到了很多视频
Oh, there, well, look, there's all kinds of videos.
嘿 你有空吗?
Hey, you got a sec?
嗨 当然
Hi. Sure.
我是想能再谈谈这笔钱的事
I was hoping we could talk about the money again.
- 亲爱的 忘了这件事吧  - 不 不 不
- Oh, sweetie, just forget about it.  - No, no, no, no,
听我说 我知道昨晚的谈话有点尴尬
hear me out. I know things got a little weird last night.
在我们嘿咻完之后 把一个装满钱的信封放在我的化妆台上
Well, leaving an envelope full of cash on my dresser after sex
就是很尴尬啊
would count as weird.
我觉得我想到了很好的解决办法
Well, I think I came up with a pretty good solution.
我们干嘛不把钱存进我们的联名账户里?
Why don't we just put the money in a joint account?
这是我们第一笔共同财产
It'll be our first money together.
我们可以用它来办婚礼 度蜜月
We can use it for the wedding, the honeymoon, whatever.
知道吗 这主意棒极了 我很喜欢!
You know what, that's great. I love that!
你当然会喜欢... 我又不只是床上天才
Yeah, of course you do... I'm not just a genius in bed.
你当然是啦 宝贝
You sure are, baby.
你们想要点私人空间吗?
You two want to be alone?
我想告诉你 我知道你干嘛不想要这笔钱了...
I want you to know I get why you don't want the money...
你有了新工作 你很兴奋
you've got this new job, you're excited
自己能经济独立了...
about being financially independent...
我真的很为你自豪
and I am nothing but proud of you.
太谢谢你了
Oh, thank you so much.
听到你这么说 我真是太高兴了
It feels so good to hear you say that.
我只是想让你知道
And I want you to know
我明白我的工作改变了
that I get this job kind of changes
我们关系里的平衡
the balance in our relationship,
但是... 我不想对此漠不关心
and... I'm trying to be sensitive to that.
什么?
What?
我只是觉得也许你对这笔钱
Well, I just think that maybe you're a little hung up
这么较真 是因为我现在没那么依赖你了
on the money because I'm less reliant on you now,
你有点怕
and that's a little scary.
恩
Hmm.
也许吧
Maybe.
或者也许我只是想做点体贴的事
Or maybe I tried to do something nice
也许因为你有控制欲
and maybe you had a problem with it
所以对这个很有意见
because of your control issues.
控制欲?
Control issues?
也许吧
Maybe.
或者... 也许...
Or... maybe...
现在我不再是个没工作的女演员
now that I'm no longer an out-of-work actress
付不起自己的晚饭钱
who can't pay for her own dinner,
这让你缺乏安全感了
that makes you a little insecure.
真不敢相信你竟然这么说
Well, I can't believe you'd say that.
你知道我对自己缺乏安全感有多没安全感的
You know how insecure I am about my insecurities.
我很抱歉
You know what? I'm sorry.
为钱的事情争吵真是太傻了
It's stupid to fight over money.
我也很抱歉 我们将来是要
Yeah, I'm sorry, too. We're about to share
共度余生的
the rest of our lives together.
这是我们的钱... 干嘛要分你我?
It's our money... who cares who has it?
你说得对... 干嘛要分?
You're right... who cares?
把那钱从我的裤子口袋里拿出来
Get that money out of my back pocket
不然我就掰断你的手指
or I will break your fingers.
这么久以来 我都不知道
All this time I never knew
这下面有蒸汽隧道
there were steam tunnels down here.
很多大学都有的
Most universities have them.
我本科在读的时候 在里面待了三天
When I was an undergrad, I spent three days in one
想要加入姐妹会
pledging a sorority.
后来加入了吗?
Did you get in?
没有 她们把我给忘了
No. They forgot I was there.
但蒸汽真的打通了我的毛孔
But it really opened up my pores.
根据我的调查
Well, according to my research,
这个出入口下面的蒸汽隧道
the steam tunnels below this access point
应该是最接近矿洞环境的
should be the closest analog to the mines.
肯定会比健身房的
This is gonna be so much more accurate
桑拿室更为精确
than the steam room at the gym.
而且 在这里也不会看到
Plus, there's almost no chance
我们那些半裸着的同事
we'll see any of our coworkers half naked.
或者是全裸的 我很喜欢Howard
Or totally naked. I love Howard,
但这家伙真是不知耻
but the dude needs a little shame.
好了 Amy 这个对讲机给你
All right, Amy, this walkie-talkie is yours.
如果我们遇上麻烦 我会呼叫你
If we run into any problems, I'll contact you.
如果发生了什么不好的事 处理流程还记得吗?
And if anything bad happens, what's the rule?
先救你 有时间再回去救Raj
Save you first, come back for Raj only if there's time.
我们不会有事的
We're going to be fine.
Sheldon 我真的很欣慰
Sheldon, I'm really impressed
你愿意尝试这个
you're willing to try this.
说真的 这真是集合了
Well, admittedly, this brushes up
我所有讨厌的元素 又热又小
against my well-known aversions to heat, small places,
地下空间
going below floor-level,
潮湿 舱门 梯子
dampness, hatches, ladders,
黑暗 回声
darkness, echoes,
还得用家得宝买来的桶当便壶
and eliminating in Home Depot buckets.
最后这条还是挺新的 但我有感觉
That last one is quite new, but I have a feeling
这个很有潜力变成我最讨厌的
that's gonna rocket to the top of the list.
我已经在出汗了
I'm sweating already.
作为在你下面的人 你不说我也知道
Yeah, as the person beneath you, allow me to say, I know.
有多热?
How hot is it?
我来看看 704度?
Uh, let's see. 704?
不 等等 这是时间
No, wait, it's on "clock."
好吧 真正的答案也没好多少
No, the real answer isn't much better.
102度
102 degrees.
这就是我们想要的
Well, that's what we wanted.
- 和矿下的温度一样高  - 没错
- This is as hot as the mines will be.  - True.
Sheldon模拟下矿日志 第一段
Sheldon's Mine Simulation Log, entry one.
Koothrappali一直喋喋不休说废话
Koothrappali's restating of the obvious
快把我烦死了
is already getting on my nerves.
非常感谢你们能来
Thanks again for having us.
噢 小事一桩 你们想找我们聊些什么?
Oh, of course. What did you guys want to talk about?
呃 你知道的 我们现在已经订婚了
Well, you know, now that we're engaged,
我们想问一下你们夫妻之间是如何解决财政问题的
we had some questions about how you handle money as a couple.
我就说过他们叫我们来不是为了玩换妻游戏的
I told you they weren't gonna ask us to swing with them.
我可没觉得他们会这么想
I didn't think they were going to.
我只是想找个法子
I just wanted to have a way to say no
在不伤害Leonard幼小心灵的前提下拒绝他们
without hurting Leonard's feelings.
好吧... 一点没伤害啊
Well... nailed it.
所以你们想知道些什么
So what did you want to know?
呃 你们是否因为钱吵过架?
Well, do you guys ever fight over money?
当然 时不时的
Sure, sometimes.
我是说 鉴于我比Howie要多赚好多钱
I mean, it can be a little awkward
这着实有些尴尬
since I make so much more money than Howie.
你没必要强调 "多得多"
You didn't have to say "so much more."
是啊 我没必要 不过为了追求准确性
Well, I didn't have to, but for the sake of accuracy
我还是觉得有必要
I felt that I should.
结婚的时候 我也带了
I brought a lot of significant assets
不少重要的财产呢
into the relationship, too.
比如? 不完整的星际迷航收藏?
Like what? Your incomplete set of Star Trek collector plates?
告诉你 我刚在eBay上
For your information, I just bought the last one
把它补齐了
I needed on eBay.
未经我同意?
Without asking me?
拍卖只剩最后三分钟了
There were only three minutes left in the auction
而且那是一个不吸烟人士出手的几乎全新的Scotty手办
and it was a mint condition Scotty from a smoke-free home.
Howie 多少钱?
How much, Howie?
没多少的
Not a lot.
到底多少钱
How much?
我们别在朋友们面前说这事了吧
Let's not talk about this in front of our friends.
比猎鹰训练学校贵吗?
Was it more or less than falconry school?
我说了多少遍那是高朋网团购的
For the tenth time, that was a Groupon.
打死我都不和他换妻
Like I would swing with him.
你还好吗
How you feeling?
还行吧
Good.
稍微有点幽闭恐惧
Little claustrophobic.
我们把设备搭起来吧
Let's set up the equipment.
能帮助转移你的注意力
It'll help take your mind off of it.
矿工们经常唱一些小曲子来提升士气
Miners often sang mining songs to keep their spirits up.
你知道什么挖矿曲么?
Do you know any mining songs?
只知道热门的
Just the hits.
# 在地牢一般的黑暗中 #
# Where it's dark as a dungeon #
# 如露珠一般湿润 #
# And it's damp as the dew #
挺不错啊
That's pretty.
# 有着几倍的危险 #
# Where the dangers are double #
# 几乎没有快乐 #
# And the pleasures are few #
# 从来没有雨水 #
# Where the rain never falls #
# 也看不见阳光 #
# And the sun never shines #
# 是啊 和地牢一般的黑暗 #
# Yes, it's dark as a dungeon #
# 在这深深的矿井之中 #
# Way down in the mine #
这歌好像比我想象的要阴暗一些
It's a little more bleak than I thought.
# 啊 我祈祷当我去世的时候 #
# Well, I pray when I dead #
# 随着时间的流逝 #
# And the ages shall roll #
# 我的身子越来越黑 #
# That my body will blacken #
# 然后化成煤矿 #
# And turn into coal #
越来越阴森了
Getting kind of grim.
# 然后我站在门口 #
# Then I'll look from the door #
# 在我天堂般的家园门口 #
# Of my heavenly home #
# 为那些矿工感到怜惜 #
# And pity the miner #
# 那些挖着我可怜的遗骨的矿工们 #
# That mines my poor bones. #
(著名女歌手 曾主演汉娜蒙塔纳)
够了够了 接下来唱点麦莉的曲子吧?
Okay. How 'bout a little Miley Cyrus next?
他是什么人?
Who's he?
说到浪费钱
Talk about wasted money.
那么最近是谁的信用卡没有及时还款
What about the late fees on our credit card
导致最近我们又被罚钱了?
because somebody didn't pay the bill on time?
哼 如果我不是在忙这忙那
Well, maybe I would have paid it
说不定就有空去交钱了
if I wasn't also doing everything else around here.
哦 你是说我无所事事吗?
Oh, you're saying I don't do anything around here.
看我的家务表
Look at my chore chart.
- 她给他弄了个家务表  - 看到了
- She made him a chore chart.  - I see it.
"洗碗" 那栏有一颗星
"Do the dishes." There's a star right there.
看你可怜才给你的 把水弄到烤盘上
That was a pity star. Putting water in the roasting pan
就那么留在水池里可不算洗了碗
and leaving it in the sink is not doing the dishes.
烤盘得先浸泡一下 你又不是不知道
That pan had to soak and you know it.
好吧 要是没拿到零花钱
Well, don't come crying to me
别哭着来找我
when you don't get your allowance.
那不是零花钱
It's not an allowance.
那是薪水!
It's a stipend!
而且我们讨论过的 不要当着朋友们的面
And we said we weren't gonna call it an allowance
叫它零花钱
in front of my friends.
我通常不吃柠檬棒
I usually don't like lemon bars,
但这玩意儿真的很好吃
but th-these are really good.
于是 以汉娜蒙塔纳的身份 麦莉
So, as Hannah Montana, Miley
是一个风靡全球的明星
was a world-famous pop star.
但是之后她会像普通女孩一样
But then she would take off her wig and go to school
脱下假发去上学
like a normal girl.
要知道 她那个年纪
Which, I don't have to tell you,
就这一点就够头疼的了
at that age, is its own headache.
这不科学
That's preposterous.
她怎么做到带个假发就能不被认出来?
How would she go unrecognized just by wearing a wig?
可你为什么觉得超人戴上眼镜
But you're okay with Superman concealing his identity
就能隐藏身份啊?
with a pair of glasses?
他又不是只戴一副眼镜
He doesn't just put on a pair of glasses.
他还把他的卷发往后梳了
He combs back his curlicue
并且言谈举止变得温文尔雅了
and affects a mild-mannered personality.
你们在下面还好吗?
You guys doing okay down there?
我不是叫你用对讲机的吗!
I told you to use the walkie-talkie!
你们在下面还好吗?
You guys doing okay down there?
请保持这个频道畅通以防万一 谢谢
Please keep this channel clear for emergencies. Thank you.
我要去自动售货机那儿 有什么要带的吗
I'm going to the vending machine. Do you want anything?
这是一次模拟测试 我们必须
This is a simulation. We have to survive
依靠我们带下来的供给生存下来
on the supplies we brought.
好吧 就是随口一问
Okay, just checking.
我们应该叫她弄点洋葱圈来
We should have asked her to get some Funyuns.
你不可能在地下一英里处的地方
You're not going to have Funyuns
搞到什么洋葱圈
when we're a mile below the surface of the Earth.
如果我们把它们带下来了呢?
What if we brought them down with us?
带一些洋葱圈来吧
We'll take some Funyuns.
还要别的吗?
Anything else?
再来点薄荷派
Some York Peppermint Patties,
(德州人民最爱的饮料)
几罐"胡椒博士"...
a couple of Dr. Peppers, and...
你跑去百思买看看有没有卖便携DVD机
run to Best Buy and see if they have a portable DVD player
和汉娜蒙塔纳的第一季
and season one of a show called Hannah Montana.
让她买第二季
Have her get season two.
第一季还在铺垫剧情
Season one, it was still finding itself.
抱歉让你们见丑了
Sorry you guys had to see that.
没关系
Oh don't apologize. Yeah.
就只是我们比较难假装什么都没发生而已
It just makes it a lot harder to pretend it never happened.
一说到钱Howie就有点敏感
Money's a sensitive subject for Howie
我们收入差距有点大
because of the difference in our income.
他很不开心吗?
It really bothers him?
当然 即使现在还是有男人当家
Well, sure. There's still a lot of pressure
的舆论压力
on guys to be providers.
所以 虽然他为我感到高兴
So even though he's happy for me,
他自己还是挺难过的
it's just a little tough on him.
- 啊哦  - 怎么?
- Uh-oh.  - What?
呃
Well,
如果我销售做得好
if I do well in sales,
也许我以后赚的钱会比你多得多
I could end up making a lot more money than you.
没问题 从小
Not a problem. I grew up with a mother
我妈财产上气场上就碾压我爸
who emasculated my father financially
所以...
and in every other aspect of his life, so...
我觉得爱情就是那样的
really, it's what I think love looks like.
我一会回来 去看看他
I'll be right back. I'm gonna go check on him.
也许我们来了凡倒是好事
Maybe it's a good thing we came here.
- 至少知道我们不该做什么了  - 是啊
- It's like a lesson in what not to do.  - Yeah.
我不想因为钱什么的跟你吵架
I don't want something dumb like money to come between us.
不会的 我们一定会在婚前
It won't. Let's just promise to figure this kind of stuff out
把它处理好
before we get married.
你干嘛这么霸道?!
Why are you being so bossy?!
你干嘛这么孩子气?
Why are you being a baby?
我没有! 我是个大人了
I'm not a baby! I'm a grown man,
我铺好床了 奖给我的小星星呢?
and I made the bed. Now where's my star?
- 该走了?  - 等等
- Should we go?  - Hang on.
我想知道他能不能得到星星
I want to see if he gets the star.
这热度简直残忍
Oh, this heat is brutal.
作为一个从热带大陆的印度来的人
As someone from the tropical subcontinent of India,
你知道在潮湿环境中扇扇子
you should know that fanning yourself in a humid environment
只会让你体温升高吧
only raises your body temperature.
哈 怪不得原来仆人们给我扇扇子的时候
Huh. That does explain why the servants used to look so hot
他们看起来那么热呢
while they were fanning me.
先别想这有多不舒服了
Let's get our minds off how uncomfortable we are.
我们可以再读几个表
We could take some more simulated instrument readings.
目前我的重心
My major focus
在于控制我的密闭恐惧症
at the moment is keeping my claustrophobia at bay.
- 控制的怎么样?  - 你说呢
- How's that going?  - You tell me.
我觉得我快窒息了
I feel like I can't breathe,
已经在想把你撕成两半
and I am tempted to crack you open
从你的肺里吸出空气了
and suck the air right out of your lungs.
Sheldon 如果你受不了 我们就不继续了
Sheldon, if this is too much, we can stop.
不能停
We're not stopping.
你也不用把我头咬掉吧
You don't have to bite my head off.
对不起
I apologize.
我...
I j...
我内心满是挣扎
I'm plagued by an internal struggle.
如果你肯用那个桶子
If you would just use the bucket,
你肯定会舒服很多
you'd be so much more comfortable.
我是内心纠结
My struggle is emotional.
喔 是Amy吗?
Oh. Is it Amy?
是暗物质
It's dark matter.
我涉足弦理论的时候
When I entered the field
我当时是个神童
of string theory, I was a prodigy.
我慢慢升到令人尊敬的地位
I rose to a position of respect,
我还以为我的事业
and I assumed my career would continue
会一直这样稳步上升
on that upward trajectory.
结果现在我三十多了
Now here I am in my 30s,
一切又回到原点
I'm back at square one.
说实话 我很害怕
And, frankly, it's frightening.
Sheldon 你知道我害怕的时候都想什么吗?
Sheldon, you know what I think of when I'm scared?
旅行者
Voyager.
你是说旅行者空间探测器
Voyager the space probe
还是那个星际迷航电视剧?
or Voyager the Star Trek TV show?
探测器
The space probe.
那就好 我现在太热了 没有精力
Good. Because I am too hot and tired
跟你说那电视剧有多烂
to go on about how much I hate Voyager the TV show.
我出生那年
By the time I was born,
旅行者一号的任务就结束了
Voyager 1's mission was supposed to be over.
探测了
It had seen
木星与土星及其卫星与环
Jupiter and Saturn and all their moons,
但它没有停下脚步
but it kept going.
我离开印度来到美国
When I left India for America,
是我人生中最恐惧的时候
I was never more scared in my life.
未来的一切都是未知
I had no idea what lay ahead.
一旦我开始害怕 我就会开始想...
Whenever I feel that way, I think about how...
旅行者还在宇宙里
Voyager is still out there
在太阳系之外
somewhere beyond our solar system,
根本没人能想到他能走这么远
going further than anyone ever thought it could.
别走! 你能行的!
Don't leave! You can do this!
Sheldon 没事吧?
Sheldon, is everything okay?
来不及救Koothrappali了
It's too late for Koothrappali.
快走!
Let's go!
11分钟 比我想的要久
11 minutes. That's longer than I thought.
跑到我衣服里了!
They're in my shirt!
衣服里! 跑到我衣服里了!
They're in my shirt! They're in my shirt!
这绝对是最好玩的
Okay, this is definitely the most fun thing we can do
用钱的方式了
with the money.
我可从来没在这么一堆钱上面做过
I've never done it on a big old pile of cash before.
"我也没有 Leonard 也是我的第一次呢"
"Me neither, Leonard. It's my first time, too."
抱歉我在钱的事情上让你伤心了
I'm so sorry I made you feel bad about the money stuff.
- 没事的  - 不 对不起
- It's okay.  - No, it's not okay.
我想跟你成为伴侣 平等的关系
I want us to be partners, equals.
成熟感情中的两个成年人
Adults in a mature relationship.
我也想这样
I want that, too.
好 我们谈谈你的生日派对吧
Now, let's talk about your birthday party.
要玩真人镭射CS CS!
Ooh, laser tag, laser tag. Oh!
真的要我写下来吗?
Do you really need me to transcribe this?
你不是帮我写
You're not doing it for me.
你是在帮助未来的人们
You're doing it for future generations
用我的血泪换他们的幸福
who will benefit from my struggle.
Sheldon的模拟下矿日志
Sheldon's Mine Simulation Log,
第四段:
entry four:
我的巧克力化了
my Kit Kat has melted.
一切都没了
All is lost.
你算什么朋友?!
You call yourself a friend?!
我明明
I was trying
在帮你! 你呢 一看有危险
to help you! And at the first sign of trouble
就跑了 留下我一个人抵抗一窝老鼠!
you ran away, leaving me to fend off a family of rats!
你就是个自私的人
You're a completely selfish human being
生理上心理上的双重懦夫!
and a... and a physical and a moral coward!
他的废话还是很烦人
His statements of the obvious continue to annoy.